UNITE Communications Department Photographs 6000/037 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Communications Department Photographs
1996-2004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE)
6000/037 P
12.44 cubic feet
12.4 linear ft.
Photographs.
7563963
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 30, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 30, 2015
Biographical / Historical
UNITE, the Union of Needle Trades, Industrial, and Textile Employees was formed in 1995 after a merger between the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
In 2004 they announced they would merge with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) which created UNITE HERE.
Jay Mazur served as president of UNITE from its beginning until his retirement in 2001. Bruce Raynor was elected president at that time and served until the HERE merger.
Scope and Contents
UNITE rallies and demonstrations as well as various meetings, informational guides, family images and historical pieces
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000/032: UNITE Communications Department Joann Mort Files 6000/037: UNITE Communications Department Records 6000/037 AV: UNITE Communications Department Audio-Visual Materials
Textile workers--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees.; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Photographs; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees --Photographs; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Communications Department--Photographs; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Photographs
7563963
- UNITE! (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Liz Clairborne - 4/8/03
- UNITE! - Fall-Winter 1999, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  UNITE Magazine; UNITE - Fall-Winter 1999; UNITE 1996 magazine; UNITE - Winer and Fall-Winter 1999; UNITE 1996
- UNITE! -- Summer 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- UNITE! - Oct. 2000 - Special Election Issue (Box 1, Folder 4)
- UNITE! -- Fall 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- UNITE! - Summer 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- UNITE! -- Spring 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- UNITE! -- Winter 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- UNITE! -- Winter 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- UNITE! -- Spring 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- UNITE! -- Summer 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- UNITE! -- Fall - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  UNITE - Fall 2001/Spring 2002; Sweat Shop-Old Stuff; UNITE Magazine - Fall 2001
- UNITE! -- Winter 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  UNITE - Winter 2002 - Cover Pix - Lolland pages
- UNITE! -- Fall 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- UNITE! -- Summer 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- UNITE! -- Spring 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- UNITE! -- Magazine -- Fall - 2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  UNITE Magazine - Conv. '03 - Clark Jones Photographs; UNITE Pictures - Fall 2003; UNITE Magazine - Con '03 - Fall '03; UNITE - Conv. '03 - UNITE Magazine
- UNITE! Magazine -- Summer 2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- UNITE! Magazine -- Spring 2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- UNITE! - Spring 2004, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  UNITE Spring '03-'04 / UINITE HERE - Fall '04 / Industrial Relations / UNITE logos
- En Espaola/UNITE! - Spanish Pages - 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Spanish Election Special
- UNITE HERE - Fall 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  UNITE HERE - Fall -- 2004 - Lallan's final photographs; UNITE HERE - Fall 2004 - Photograph pages 9-17
- Lear Auto Parts; Berne, IN - Local 295C -- 9/3/2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  22 photographs; negatives
- Castleford - 5/13/2003 -- (Burbury) by Gary Schoichet (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Contact sheets
- Libroshirt -- 01/07/2003 - Lykens, PA (Box 2, Folder 3)
  13 photographs
- Local 62-32 -- Members at Edith Lance, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  20 photographs -- photos by Sandra Mendoza -- 11/2002
- Bruce Raynor & Shelly Silver @ Martin Greenfield in Brooklyn -- 10/4/2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  65 photographs -- negatives --- proof sheet
- Made in NY Even Photos -- 11/22/2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- UNITE! Rally -- Amhil, Toronto -- May, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  7 photographs
- UNITE Labour Day 2002 -- Toronto, Canada (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Polywrap -- Photographs of Maria Lourdes Manansala -- Montreal, Canada (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Photos marked as "Canadian photos from Tullia" -- 4 photographs
- Richards Wilcox - Mississauga, ON by David Smiley --- 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  2 photographs; contact sheets
- UNITE - Brylane / Union vote, Brylane, 5/10/2003 -- Indianapolis, IN; Photographs by Ron Hoskins (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fred's ---- 9/7/2002 -- by Lisa Wadely (Box 2, Folder 12)
  102 photographs -- negatives
- Bruce Raynor - slides (Box 2, Folder 13)
  86 slides
- UNITE Fred's Press Conference -- May 19, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- A00599 (note says two rolls on CD) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Fred's for Billboard; Ana Maria Arujo, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  18 photographs
- Fred's; Political Activity; Jesse Jackson (Box 2, Folder 17)
  210 photographs; negatives
- Fred's (Contact sheets) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Buser - Helena, Ark. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  191 slides
- Liz Claiborne Action, NYC - photocopies of contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Liz Claiborne- Nat'l. Contract Negotiations -- 5/13/2003 --- by Gary Schoichet (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Immigration Rally 2002 -- Mid-Atlantic Joint Bd. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  2 photographs
- Citizenship workshop in Philadelphia (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Triangle Fire -- contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 24)
- UNITE! Lobby Day - 4/30/2003 -- Contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Photocopies of contact sheets
- Jay Rockefeller -- (political file) --- 8/31/2002 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  1 photograph
- NAACP Convention -- Houston, Texas -- 7/6-11/2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  negatives; letter
- Pataki - leafleting -- 11/4/2002 -- NYC - by Dave Sanders (Box 2, Folder 28)
- NAACP Convention -- Houston, TX --- 7/6-11/2002 "Canadian photos from Tullia" (Box 2, Folder 29)
  15 photographs
- NAACP Convention -- Houston, TX -- pic of Clayola Brown (Box 2, Folder 30)
  1 photograph; negative
- Ed Rendell (political campaign) -- Pennsylvania, Ohio, New Jersey (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Ed Rendell (political campaign) Pennsylvania, Ohio, New Jersey (Box 2, Folder 32)
  3 photographs
- Mcgreevey -- NYC by Vinnie Ramirez (Box 2, Folder 33)
  8 photographs
- Retirees --- Philadelphia - giving out leaflets at Tiffany's (Box 2, Folder 34)
  6 photographs
- Retirees - Gucci Action -- 6/27/2002 -- Florida (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Retirees -- RX drugs --- 5/28/2002 -- on bus to Canada (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Pillowtex (textiles) -- 8/2002 -- Hanover, PA by Cliff Clark (Box 2, Folder 37)
  9 photographs
- Pillowtex (textiles) California - Summer 2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  22 photographs
- Yale -- 9/2003 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  15 photocopied photographs; 98 photographs
- GAP -- photos of poster & clothing by Mary Kay? (Box 2, Folder 40)
  20 photographs; negatives
- GAP -- Philadelphia Rally --- 10/9/2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  48 photographs; negatives
- GAP --- empty folder (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Milwaukee No Sweat Law (Box 2, Folder 43)
- UNITE Lobby Display (1999) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  photo copies of contact sheets and photographs; Display 2, Display 3 (1999); Display 1 (1999); UNITED Lobby Display; Display 6, Display 7 (1999); Displays 1999; Display 4 (1999), Display 5
- UNITE (Box 3, Folder 2)
  French & Spanish - 12/11/2005; French Conf.; Uniback Master; Consolidated Brochures (General & Spanish); UNITE Sticker Flyer; Uniform Justice Extra Pix; Consolidated Brochures; flyers
- Campaign for the Future (flyers) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Politic Action manual -- 2002; UNITE -- Spring/Summer/Winter -- 2001, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Brylane Photos -- 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Calendar -- 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- UNITE! Calendar -- 2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Calendar
- Procurement Display - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Union Square (Box 3, Folder 9)
  2 disk
- Scholarship Posters (1998-1999) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  1 disk
- GAP Ad, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  GAP Ad - Oct. '02; J. Sheinkman - Mostly Edward W. Clark; ILGWU - Mazur Sheinkman Tyler
- Jesse Jackson --- 3/1997-10/1997; Liz Claiborne, Ross Perot, Dole -- 1996, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  37 photographs
- NYC -- Worker's Ed. Center --- Fall 1999; Gary Schoichet (Box 3, Folder 13)
  147 photographs
- Liz Claiborne - 4/8/03, 2003 (Box 5)
- UNITE 1996 (Box 6)
- UNITE Fall/Winter 1999 (1 of 2) (Box 7)
- UNITE Magazine 1996 (Box 8)
- UNITE Fall/Winter 1999 (2 of 2) (Box 9)
- Amy's Stuff (Box 10)
- UNITE Magazine -- July '03 -- Lallan's HD -- Summer '02, 2002-2003 (Box 11)
- UNITE Summer 1999 (Box 12)
- UNITE! Summer 1999 -- High resolution scans (Box 13)
- High Resolution -- Oct. 2000 (1 of 2) (Box 14)
- UNITE -- High resolution -- Oct. 2000 (2 of 2) (Box 15)
- UNITE -- Winter/Fall 2000 (1 of 2) (Box 16)
- UNITE -- Fall/2000 (2 of 2) (Box 17)
- UNITE Fall/2000 (2 of 2) (Box 18)
- UNITE Summer 2000 Scans (1 of 2) (Box 19)
- UNITE Summer 2000 Scans (2 of 2) (Box 20)
- UNITE 2000 Spring (Box 21)
- UNITE 2000 Spring (Box 22)
- UNITE Winter 2000 (Box 23)
- UNITE Winter 2001 Pixs (1 of 2) (Box 24)
- UNITE Winter 2001 Pixs (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 25)
- UNITE Winter 2001 (Box 26)
- UNITE! -- Spring 2001 -- High resolution scans (Box 27)
- UNITE -- Summer 2001 (1 of 2) (Box 28)
- UNITE Summer 2001 (2 of 2) (Box 29)
- UNITE Fall 2001 (1 of 2) (Box 30)
- UNITE Fall 2001 (2 of 2) (Box 31)
- Fall '01/Spring '02 -- Lallan's computer, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
- UNITE Magazine - Fall '01, 2001 (Box 33)
- Fall 2001/Spring 2002 -- Sweat shop/Old stuff, 2001-2002 (Box 34)
- UNITE! Building UNITE - 2002 in review (1 of 2) (Box 35)
- UNITE! - Building UNITE -- 2002 in review (2 of 2) (Box 36)
- Winter '02 -- Cover pix - Lollan pages, 2002 (Box 37)
- UNITE pictures -- Fall 2002 (Box 38)
- UNITE! Scans -- Summer 2002 (1 of 2) (Box 39)
- UNITE! Scans -- Summer 2002 (2 of 2) (Box 40)
- UNITE Spring 2002 (Box 41)
- UNITE Scans (Hi-Res) (disk 1 of 2) (Box 42)
- UNITE Scans (Hi-Res) (disk 2 of 2) (Box 43)
- UNITE Fall '03 pages 2-9 Lallan, 2003 (Box 44)
- Conv. '03 UNITE Magazine, 2003 (Box 45)
- UNITE Mag Con '03 Fall '03, 2003 (Box 46)
- UNITE Fall 2003 pictures (Box 47)
- UNITE Mag -- Conv '03 -- Clark Jones photos, 2003 (Box 48)
- UNITE Summer '03 (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 49)
- UNITE Summer '03 (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 50)
- UNITE Hires -- Spring 2003 (1 of 2) (Box 51)
- UNITE Hires -- Spring 2003 (2 of 2) (Box 52)
- UNITE Spring '03, 2003 (Box 53)
- UNITE HERE -- Annual report -- Fall '05, 2005 (Box 54)
- UNITE pictures (2 of 2) (Box 55)
- UNITE pictures (1 of 2) (Box 56)
- UNITE Spring '03-'04/Fall '04/Industrial relations/UNITE, 2003-2004 (Box 57)
- Spanish election special '00, 2000 (Box 58)
- UNITE HERE Fall 2004 (English) (Box 59)
- UNITE HERE Fall 2004 (photos pages 9-17) (Box 60)
- UNITE HERE Fall '04 -- Lallan's final pics, 2004 (Box 61)
- Burbury -- 5/13/2003 -- Castleford Ltd. (Box 62)
- Christina Pena -- photos: Noelle Theard (Perry Ellis) (Box 63)
- Christina Pena - photos: Noelle Theard (Box 64)
- Made in NY event photos -- 11/22/2002 (Box 65)
- UNITE Labour Day 2002, Toronto, Canada (Box 66)
- UNITE Brylane (Box 67)
- UNITE Fred's Press Conf. -- May 19, 2003 (Box 68)
- A00599 (Box 69)
- Fred's for Billboard (Box 70)
- Liz Claiborne neg. (Box 71)
- UNITE! Lobby Day -- 4/30/2005 (Box 72)
- Contact sheets (Box 73, Folder 1)
- Contact Sheets (Box 73, Folder 2)
- Patki (Box 73, Folder 3)
  11 photographs; contact sheets
- With These Hands - Crafts Feature (Box 73, Folder 4)
  12 Photographs and news clippings
- Display 4 (1999), Display 5 (1999) (Box 74)
- Displays 1-3 (1999) (Box 75)
- Displays 6-7 (1999) (Box 76)
- UNITE Lobby Displays 1-3 (1999) (Box 77)
- Display 1 (1999) (Box 78)
- Displays 2-3 (1999) (Box 79)
- Consolidated brochures (Box 80)
- Uniform Justice Extra Pix (Box 81)
- UNITE Sticker Flyer (Box 82)
- Consolidated Brochures (General & Spanish) (Box 83)
- Uniback Master (Box 84)
- Consolidated Brochures (French) (Box 85)
- Consolidated Brochures (French & Spanish) (Box 86)
- UNITE - Spring, Summer, Winter (2001) (Box 87)
- Politic Action Manual (2002, Spanish); Politic Action (Box 88)
- Brylane Photos (Box 89)
- UNITE Brylane campaign photos -- 24 October - 2002 (Box 90)
- Calendar 2002 (Box 91)
- Procurement Display 4/99, 1999 (Box 92)
- ILGWU - Mazur Sheinkman, Tyler (Box 93)
- J. Sheinkman, Mostly Edward W. Clark (Box 94)
- GAP AD -- Oct. '02, 2002 (Box 95)
- Starbuck's/Cintas rally -- 4/23/2003 (Box 96)